# Jonathan Mercedes-Feliz

Department of Physics, University of Connecticut, 196 Auditorium Road, U-3046, Storrs, CT 06269, USA

■ jonathan.mercedes\_feliz@uconn.edu | 🖸 github.com/JonMer1198 | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/jonathanmercedesfeliz | 📵 0000-0002-8390-6726

## Personal Profile\_

A PhD candidate at the University of Connecticut under Professor Daniel Anglés-Alcázar. His current work is using state-of-the-art simulations from the Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project, to study the growth and impact of massive black holes in galaxies at cosmic noon ( $z \sim 2$ ), focusing on massive galaxies near the peak of cosmic star formation and active galactic nuclei (AGN) activity.

#### Education

#### **University of Connecticut**

Storrs, CT

PhD in Physics

Aug 2018 - Current

- Field of Study: Astronomy
- Cosmological hyper-refinement simulations of quasar fueling and feedback at cosmic noon

#### **University of Connecticut**

Storrs, CT

MS in Physics

Aug 2018 - Dec 2020

• Courses: Mathematical Physics, Thermodynamics & Statistical Mechanics, Electricity & Magnetism, Classical and Quantum Mechanics, Particle and Nuclear Physics, Stars and Compact Objects

#### The City University of New York at Lehman College

New York, NY

BS in Physics

Aug 2013 - May 2018

· Graduated Cum Laude

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### **University of Connecticut**

Storrs, CT

Graduate Research Assistant

Jan 2020 - Current

- Analyzed the effects of black hole feedback, in the form of fast accretion-driven winds, on a massive galaxy in high resolution cosmological hydrodynamic simulations with resolved multi-phase interstellar medium.
- Technical Skills: Python, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Ubuntu Linux, Linux tools, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

#### **University of Connecticut**

Storrs, CT

**Graduate Teaching Assistant** 

Aug 2018 - Jan 2020

- Instructing introductory astronomy labs, grading lab reports and assignments, providing feedback to students, as well as helping students achieve a higher understanding of Physics and Astronomy.
- · Assisted in redesign of the introductory astronomy lab assignments to promote smoother course work flow.
- Technical Skills: DS9
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

# American Museum of Natural History/ Center for Computational Astrophysics

New York, NY

Undergraduate Student Researcher

Jun 2017 - Aug 2018

- Identified black holes in several high resolution cosmological simulations. Analyzed simulation outputs for signatures that are potentially observable using current technology.
- Wrote iterative code to record properties of black holes and host galaxies at various points throughout their evolution, with a focus on black holes within dwarf galaxies.
- Technical Skills: Python, Numpy, Matplotlib, Git
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Logical Thinking.

JONATHAN MERCEDES-FELIZ 1 OF 3

## **Publications**

Local Positive Feedback in the Overall Negative: The impact of quasar winds on star formation in the FIRE

**First Author** cosmological simulations. **Mercedes-Feliz, J.**, Anglés-Alcázar, D., et al. 2023, submitted to MNRAS

(arXiv:2301.01784).

**First Author**Dense stellar clump formation driven by strong quasar winds in the FIRE cosmological simulations.

Mercedes-Feliz, J., Anglés-Alcázar, D., et al. 2023, in preparation.

**Co Author** The impact of AGN-driven winds on physical and observable galaxy sizes. Cochrane, R., Anglés-Alcázar, D.,

Mercedes-Feliz, J., et al. 2023, submitted to MNRAS (arxiv:2303.12858).

## Skills

**Programming** Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, Scipy, Astropy, etc.), Java, Mathematica. **Miscellaneous** Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), ŁTFX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Microsoft Office, Git.

**Soft Skills** Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

## Achievements

2020	Connecticut Space Grant, Graduate Fellowship	CT
2017-18	AstroCom NYC, Fellowship	NY
2017	Presidential Scholar, Lehman College	NY
2016	Dean's List, Lehman College	NY

## **Presentations**

Oral "Investigating Positive and Negative AGN Feedback in the FIRE cosmological simulations". AGN Winds on the Chesapeake. Easton, MD. June 2023.

**Oral** "Shaping Massive Galaxies at Cosmic Noon: Probing AGN Feedback in the FIRE Simulations". 31st Annual New England Regional Quasar and AGN Meeting. South Kingston, RI. May 2023.

**Oral** "Local Positive Feedback in the Overall Negative: The impact of quasar winds on star formation in the FIRE cosmological simulations". Invited Talk at the University of Southampton. Southampton, England. February 2023.

**Oral** "Local Positive Feedback in the Overall Negative: The impact of quasar winds on star formation in the FIRE cosmological simulations". 241st Meeting of the American Astronomical Society. Seattle, WA. January 2023.

**Oral** "Quantifying the Cosmic Web in CAMELS". Cosmic and Astrophysics with MachinE Learning Simulations Workshop. New York, NY. November 2022.

**Oral** "Local Positive Feedback in the Overall Negative: The impact of quasar winds on star formation in the FIRE simulations". 30th Annual New England Regional Quasar and AGN Meeting. Storrs, CT. May 2022.

**Oral** "Local Positive Feedback in the Overall Negative: The impact of quasar winds on star formation in the FIRE simulations". American Museum of Natural History Virtual Astro Seminar. New York, NY. May 2022.

**ePoster**"Local Positive Feedback in the Overall Negative: The impact of quasar winds on galactic star formation in the FIRE simulations". European Astronomical Society Annual Meeting. Leiden, Netherlands. July 2021.

**Poster** "Black Holes and Dwarf Galaxy Mergers". 231st Meeting of the American Astronomical Society. Washington, DC. January 2018.

**Poster** "Black Holes and Dwarf Galaxy Mergers". Society for Advancement of Chicanos/Hispanics and Native Americans in Science. Salt Lake City, Utah. October 2017.

Oral "Black Holes and Dwarf Galaxy Mergers". Center for Computational Astrophysics/Flatiron Institute Symposium.

New York, NY. August 2017

# Languages\_

JONATHAN MERCEDES-FELIZ 2 OF 3

English Native proficiencySpanish Bilingual proficiencyJapanese Elementary proficiency

JONATHAN MERCEDES-FELIZ 3 OF 3